Guide to the Harold Phelps Stokes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1908-1969; Series I; 2 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - Schurman, Jacob Gould (2), 1914 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Sevareid, Arnold Eric (2), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Seymour, Charles (9), 1920, 1922-1923, 1945, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Sherwood, Robert Emmet (2), 1952 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Shoten, Oiwa Arao (1), 1923 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Smith, Alfred Emanuel (12), 1915-1916, 1920, 1922-1923, 1927, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Smith, H. Alexander (2), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Smith, Margaret Chase (1), undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Soper, George Albert (1), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Sousa, John Philip (2), 1930 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Spender, J. A. (2), 1923 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Sterrett, J. E. (2), 1923 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Stetson, Harlan True (2), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Stevenson, Burton Egbert (1), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Stimson, Henry Lewis (12), 1914, 1929-1930, 1934, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Stoddard, Henry Luther (1), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps (1874-1958) (30), 1921-1926, 1928, 1930-1931, 1934, 1937, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps (1874-1958)(25), 1947-1953, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr. (1), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Stokes, Helen Phelps (1), 1923 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Stokes, Isaac Newton Phelps, II (2), 1957, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Stokes, W. E. D., Jr. (2), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Stone, Harlan Fiske (4), 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Strunsky, Frances (1), n. d. (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Strunsky, Robert (11), 1947, 1950-1952, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Strunsky, Simeon (37), 1921-1923, 1938-1947, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Sullivan, Mark (5), 1923, 1934-1935, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays (36), 1926, 1929-1930, 1934-1941, 1943, 1952-1953, 1955-1957, 1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Sulzberger, Iphigene Ochs (2), 1936, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Sweetser, Arthur (3), 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard (2), 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - T, 1916, 1930, 1933, 1935-1936, 1952, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Taft, Charles Phelps (5), 1933-1934, 1936, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Taft, Henry Waters (1), 1921 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Taft, Robert Alphonso (2), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Taubkin, Irvin S. (3), 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Thacher, Thomas Day (2), 1935, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Thayer, Walter N. (2), 1932, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Thomas, Norman (1), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Trudeau, Edward Livingstone (15), 1908-1910, 1913-1914, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Trudeau, Francis B. (2), 1954, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Truman, Harry S. (1), 1951 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - Tsur, Y. T. (2), 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - U, 1909, 1919-1920, 1923, 1950, 1953, 1961, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Underwood, Oscar W. (1), 1922 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Underwood, Mrs. Pierson (1), undated (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Untermyer, Samuel (11), 1927, 1929-1934 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - V, 1922, 1928, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Van Name, George Rivet (1), 1931 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Veiller, Lawrence (2), 1934 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison (18), 1910-1911, 1915-1919, 1922-1923, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - W, 1921, 1924, 1929, 1934, 1940, 1956-1957, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Wagner, Robert Ferdinand (13), 1928-1929, 1934, 1936-1937, 1939, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Wallis, James Harold (4), 1935, 1942, 1953, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Walsh, Thomas James (4), 1922-1924 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Waring, Thomas Richard (3), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - White, Elwyn Brooks (3), 1951, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - White, William Allen (5), 1926, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Wickersham, George Woodward (2), 1916 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Wiggins, James Russell (2), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Wilder, Amos Parker (3), 1911, 1921, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Wile, Frederick William (2), 1924 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Willkie, Wendell Lewis (2), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell (2), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Wise, Stephen Samuel (1), 1912 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Woods, Arthur (1), 1920 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Woodward, Thomas Mullen (2), 1938 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Wriston, Henry Merritt (2), 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Yale University Library (5), 1948, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Young, Owen D. (4), 1926, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - unidentified (Box 4, Folder 132)
- DIARIES, MEMORANDA, NOTES AND WRITINGS, 1908-1965; Series II; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Articles and essays by Stokes are placed first in this series. They are arranged alphabetically by title and the date is noted where possible. Memos and notes by Stokes are filed next. They are arranged alphabetically. Book reviews, letters to the editor, and newspaper stories by Stokes complete the series. They are arranged chronologically.
  - Arthur Brisbane, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Christianity in Japan,", 1909 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Covering the news in Washington, D. C., undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dispatches, 1919-1921, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Early Days" (St. Regis Yacht Club), 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Elvers, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Emil Ludwig on Groton,", undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Exploding the Tammany Myth,", 1933 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "The Faculty" (Yale), 1908 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Gall,", 1923 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "The Grand Central Complex,", undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Groton Celebrates its Fiftieth Year,", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Half Slave, Half Free,", 1930 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "A Man Who Will Sit at Hoover's Right" (Stimson), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "Mandates,", 1920 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Manual of the Alarm Clock,", 1918 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "New York Leads the Way,", undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Phelps-Stokes Family News Sheet, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Returning AEF, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Sing Sing, Class of '34,", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - "The Slum Doctor,", 1908 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Smith and Hoover: A Comparison,", 1928 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Paul Smith,", undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - "Some Notes on S. S." (Simeon Strunsky) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Talk Before Women's Democratic Club,", 1929 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Francis Trudeau (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Yale 1909,", 1959 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "Yale and China,", 1910? (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "Yale's Opportunity in China,", 1909 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - "Yale, the Portsmouth Treaty, and Japan,", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Diary: the disarmament conference, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Diary: trip around the world, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Memos and notes re:
    - Carl Becker (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Stephen Bonsai (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - W. B. Bryan (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Christianity (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Civil Service Reform (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Irvin S. Cobb (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - LeBaron B. Colt (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Constitutional and Parliamentary Systems (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Eisenhower's Economic Report (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Alger Hiss (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Hoover on public utility regulation (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Charles Evans Hughes (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - International control of atomic energy (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - League of Nations (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Legislative committees of inquiry (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Walter Lippmann (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - George McAneny (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Mixed economy (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - New York City and State finance (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - New York City transit (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - New York Evening Post (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Rollo Ogden (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Parole (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Power policy (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Theodore Roosevelt (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - James T. Shotwell (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Solon (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Spiritual resources (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - TVA and Constitution (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Vice-President Wallace (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - War (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Woodrow Wilson (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Book reviews by H. P. Stokes, 1938-1939, 1941-1942, 1944, 1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Letters to the editor by H. P. Stokes, 1937-1940, 1943, 1945-1947, 1952-1956, 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
  - Newspaper articles (mss.), 1912, 1920-1921, 1923, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1911, 1915-1916, 1919-1921 (Box 6, Folder 49-54)
  - Newspaper clippings (trip to Alaska), 1923 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1924, 1928, 1932-1934, 1936-1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 56-60)
- NEWSPAPER FILE, 1913-1917, 1919-1924; Series III
  The numbers listed in the title refer to volume numbers. These twenty-three volumes are arranged chronologically. There is a gap in 1917 and 1918 due to the first World War. Two lost volumes cause a gap in 1922. The twenty-three are indexed on file cards that direct the researcher to the proper volume and page number for a given subject.
  For the first series of file cards, the volume numbers refer to the Arabic numbers (vol.s 1-6). For the second series, they refer to Roman numerals, so that in box 12 or 13 a reference to vol. 6 is really a reference to vol. VI (= vol. 14). There are cards for the missing volumes XIII and XIV; but there appear to be no cards for volumes 7 and 8.
  The volumes have been microfilmed and discarded; they are now available as Hist. MSS Film HM 108.
  - Volume 1, 1913 December - 1914 May
    General
    See Film HM 108, Reel 1.
  - Volume 2, 1914 May - 1914 November
  - Volume 3, 1914 November - 1915 April
  - Volume 4, 1915 April - 1916 February
    See Film HM 108, Reel 2.
  - Volume 5, New York Constitutional Convention of 1915, 1915-1915
  - Volume 6, 1916 February - 1916 August
  - Volume 7, 1916 August - 1917 May
    See Film HM 108, Reel 3.
  - Volume 8, 1919 January - 1919 March
  - Volume 9 (I), 1919 September - 1919 November
  - Volume 10 (II), 1919 November - 1920 January
  - Volume 11 (III), 1920 January - 1920 April
  - Volume 12 (IV), 1920 April - 1920 June
    See Film HM 108, Reel 4.
  - Volume 13 (V), 1920 June - 1920 July
  - Volume 14 (VI), 1920 July - 1920 August
  - Volume 15 (VII), 1920 August - 1920 October
    See Film HM 108, Reel 5.
  - Volume 16 (VIII), 1920 October - 1920 December
  - Volume 17 (IX), 1920 December - 1921 January
    See Film HM 108, Reel 6.
  - Volume 18 (X), 1921 January - 1921 April
  - Volume 19 (XI), 1921 April - 1921 August
  - Volume 20 (XII), 1921 September - 1922 March
    See Film HM 108, Reel 7.
  - Volume 21 (XV), 1923 January - 1923 April
  - Volume 22 (XVI), 1923 April - 1923 November
  - Volume 23 (XVII), 1923 November - 1924 April
  - Index A - M, (1913-1917) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Index N - Z, (1913-1917) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Index A - L, (1919-1924) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Index M - Z, (1919-1924) (Box 13, Folder 1)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1776-1912; Series IV; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  The SUBJECT FILE is arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Alaska (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Alaskan trip of President Harding, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Andrews, Paul Shipman (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Bundy, Harvey Hollister (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bundy, McGeorge (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Burch, Robert B. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Civil liberties (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Great Britain (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger (Box 7, Folder 10-14)
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Finley, John Huston (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Klots, Allen Trafford (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Lansing, Robert (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Loomis, Alfred Lee (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - New York City and State Government (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - New York Constitutional Convention of 1915 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - New York Evening Post (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
  - New York Times (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Overseas Writers (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Proportional representation (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Public utilities (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Skull and Bones (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps (1874-1958) (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Stokes, Harold Phelps (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Strunsky, Simeon (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Strunsky, Simeon (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Simeon Strunsky's America (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Trudeau, Edward Livingstone (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Washington, D. C. transit (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Yale 1909 reunion (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 40)
- ADDITIONS, 1975-1976
  - Correspondence
    - Stokes, Harold Phelps: letters to
      - Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes (mother):
        - 1890-1909 (Box 14, Folder 41-47)
        - 1909-1918 (Box 15, Folder 48-57)
      - Helen Stokes (niece), 1918-1919 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Stokes, Harold Phelps: letters from
      - Helen Louisa Phelps Stokes:
        - 1897-1910 (Box 16, Folder 59-65)
        - 1911-1918 (Box 17, Folder 66-70)
        - 1919-1930 (Box 18, Folder 71-72)
      - King, Elizabeth, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 73-74)
      - Miscellanea: engagement, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 75)
    - Others, 1904-1930 (Box 19, Folder 76-77)
  - Diaries
    - Stokes, Harold M.P., 1896-1897 (Box 19, Folder 78)
    - Stokes, Harold Phelps, 1904-1911 (Box 19, Folder 79-83)
  - Genealogy
    - "Stokes Family News":
      - 1931-1941 (Box 20, Folder 84-94)
      - 1942-1952 (Box 21, Folder 95-105)
      - 1953-1965 (Box 22, Folder 106-118)
      - 1966-1975 (Box 23, Folder 119-124)
      - undated (Box 24, Folder 125-126)
    - Individuals:
      - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1864-1913 (Box 24, Folder 127)
      - Stokes, Anson Phelps, Jr., 1921-1939, undated (Box 24, Folder 128)
      - Stokes, Caroline P. and Robert Hunter, undated (Box 24, Folder 129)
      - Stokes, Harold Phelps:
        - General, 1890-1860 (Box 24, Folder 130-137)
        - Engagement, 1920, undated (Box 24, Folder 138)
        - Obituaries, 1949-1970 (Box 24, Folder 139)
      - Stokes, I.N.P.S., 1925-1967, undated (Box 24, Folder 140)
      - Stokes, J. G. Phelps, 1848-1952 (Box 24, Folder 141)
      - Stokes, Mildred Phelps, 1930-1967, undated (Box 24, Folder 142)
      - Stokes, Olivia Phelps, 1960-1965 (Box 24, Folder 143)
      - Stokes, Sarahmaria P., 1918-1945 (Box 24, Folder 144)
      - Stokes, W. E. D., Jr., 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 145)
      - King Family, 1920-1959 (Box 24, Folder 146)